

Manuel Vigo

My aim is to help organizations innovate through a user-centered approach. I focus on driving innovation through design research, strategy, and rapid prototyping.

I value multidisciplinary and cross-cultural teams and have been fortunate to live and work on 4 continents.

⊠ manuel.vigo@gmail.com

- www.manuelvigo.com
- in linkedin.com/in/manuelvigo/

+34 696 923 570

Languages:

English - Native Spanish - Native

Nationalities:

Peru

United States

Consulting Projects for:

- •CERN (Switzerland)
- Konica Minolta (UK)
- Ferrino (Italy)

Hobbies:

I play guitar and enjoy playing and recording music with friends. An avid reader, I enjoy literature and books on philosophy. Lately I've been brushing up on HTML and Arduino. A constant learner, curiosity is my biggest driver.

Work Experience

CERN - The European Organization for Nuclear Research

Sep 2017 - Oct 2017

Design and Innovation Intern

- •Carried out user research, co-creation sessions, and rapid prototyping, to identify opportunities and execute projects to improve the interaction between the scientific community and innovators/entrepreneurs within CERN.
- •Hosted and facilitated Design Thinking and Collaborative Design workshops.

Latin America For Less

Jan 2017 - Present

Special Projects Manager

- ·Managing SEO, and digital advertising strategy.
- Advising on web development and UX projects.

Jun 2014 - Dec 2016

Marketing and UX Manager

- •Built and led 9-person digital marketing, content, and web development teams.
- •Led design, user experience, SEO, and PPC advertising for all LAFL brands. Leading to conversion rate improvements of over 59% year-to-year.
- •Carried out design sprints to develop customized digital tools that improved user experience and efficiencies in the sales funnel.
- •Analyzed research and customer feedback to improve user-experience.
- •Managed building of new brand projects, and led the company's winning proposal for PeruDesignNet, a competition honoring innovative ideas.

Oct 2013 - Jun 2014

Marketing Manager

- •Oversaw digital marketing, advertising, website and content development.
- •Led complete redesign of websites, with a focus on mobile UX.
- •Developed and executed SEO strategy, A/B testing, and UX research

Jun 2013 - Sep 2014

Content and Social Media Coordinator

•Developed and executed content strategy for internal blog, link outreach, and, social media.

Next City

Dec 2012 - Sep 2013

Journalist and Researcher

- •Researched and wrote a weekly article series on Lima's informal economy for The Rockefeller Foundation's Informal City Dialogues.
- •Part of Future Scenarios conferences in Lima, helping participants build a framework for understanding the next decades of Lima's growth.

Peru This Week

Apr 2011 - June 2013

News Editor

· Over 700 articles written on business, economic, political, and cultural trends in Peru.

Education

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017 (expected)

IED Istituto Europeo di Design - Barcelona

Master in Design Management

Aug 2007 - Dec 2010

Florida International University

B.A in International Relations and Philosophy

1996 - 2005

Markham College

Graduated with honours. International Baccalaureate (IB) and IGCSE